## Minh Tran

#### Summary

My research interests are deep learning algorithms for visual perception tasks (object detection, segmentation, pose estimation, etc.) and path/motion planning regarding visual perception. Currently, my work involves exploring deep learning algorithms for semantic and instance segmentation tasks in images and videos. I have authored several papers, including a first-author conference paper at BMVC on instance segmentation, two first-author conference papers on medical image segmentation at ISBI and ICPR, and a first-author journal paper on medical image registration at TMI. Additionally, I have contributed to projects related to mobile robot navigation (with a first-author publication at NICS) and federated learning for autonomous driving (with a co-author publication at IV). My works have received 110 citations, and my h-index is 4.

## SKILLS

Computer Vision, Panoptic Segmentation, Deep Reinforcement Learning, Pytorch, Detectron2

## EXPERIENCE

#### AICV Lab, University of Arkansas

Graduate Research Assistant

Sep 2021 - Present

- Instance and Semantic Segmentation: Working on amodal instance segmentation (which aim to predict the whole segmentation of objects, including occluded parts); high-quality semantic segmentation on poultry and aerial imagery; medical image segmentation.
- Behaviour Understanding in Poultry Science: Working on detection, segmentation, and keypoint estimation tasks for chicken's behaviour understanding.

#### AIOZ AI

Research Engineer

Aug 2020 - Aug 2021

- Indoor Delivery Robot: Developed algorithms for localization module of an indoor self-delivery robot.
- Medical Imaging: Developed light-weight models for medical image registration.

#### EDUCATION

### University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, AR

Ph.D. in Computer Science (Advisor: Ngan Le)

Aug 2021 - Present

#### University of Science, VNU-HCM

B.Sc. Honors in Computer Science

Sep 2016 - Oct 2020

## SELECTED PUBLICATION

#### Journal Papers

• Minh Tran, et al. Light-Weight Deformable Registration Using Adversarial Learning With Distilling Knowledge, IEEE transactions on medical imaging Conference Papers

- Minh Tran, et al. AISFormer: Amodal Instance Segmentation with Transformer, In The 33rd British Machine Vision Conference, 2022
- Minh Tran, et al. SS-3DCapsNet: Self-supervised 3D Capsule Networks for Medical Segmentation on Less Labeled Data, In 2022 IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (ISBI)
- Anh Nguyen, Tuong Do, Minh Tran, et al. Deep Federated Learning for Autonomous Driving, In 2022 IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV), 2021

# OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

## AIStron: Amodal Instance Segmentation Toolbox and Benchmark

AIStron is an open-source toolbox that provides current Amodal Instance Segmentation (AIS) methods.

#### Awards

#### Rodger S. Kline Chair Scholarship

Jan 2023

 ${\it Graduate \ scholarship \ for \ top-nominated \ graduate \ students \ at \ University \ of \ Arkansas}$ 

#### Reginald R. "Barney" & Jameson A. Baxter Graduate Fellowship

Aug 2022

Graduate scholarship for top-nominated graduate students at University of Arkansas

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## CSCE 4133: Algorithms, University of Arkansas

Teaching Assistant

#### NACME Google AMLI Summer Program

Teaching Assistant

#### Services Reviewer at MICCAI 2023